{
    "question": "Jelasin tentang present perfect tense\u00a0",
    "attachments": [],
    "answers": [
        {
            "answer": "Present perfect adalah tenses yang menyatakan bahwa kejadian sudah dilakukan.<br>Rumus : S + Have/Has(Auxiliary) + V3<br>Misal : I have done my homework<br>Unsur : I = Subject<br>Have = Aux/Have/Has<br>Done = V3<br>Homework = Object<br>Umumnya ditambahkan kata Since + Time<br>Jadi : I have done my homework since this morning<br><br>",
            "attachments": []
        },
        {
            "answer": "present perfect itu berhubungan dengan kejadian yang sudah selesai. kata kuncinya sih ada kata \"sudah\", \"baru saja\", dsb.<br><br>misalkan \"saya sudah mengerjakan PR\", atau i have done my homework<br><br>",
            "attachments": []
        }
    ],
    "related_questions": [
        {
            "slug": "ubahlah-menjadi-indirect-speech-1-kiki-said-whats-will-you-962",
            "question": "Ubahlah menjadi indirect speech!    1. Kiki said '' What's will you buy in the mall?''\r\n2. Mrs. Maria said '' Can you speak englsh well?''\r\n3. Yuda said Tika '' Are you from Surabaya?''",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "kalau kalimatnya pertanyaan sebaiknya jangan pakai &#039;said&#039; tapi pakai &#039;asked (verb 2 dari ask)&#039;, jadinya...<br>1. Kiki asked me what would I buy in the mall : menggunakan me karena menceritakan kembali<br>2. Mrs. Maria asked me if I could speak English very well\u00a0: menggunakan me karena menceritakan kembali<br>3. Yuda asked Tika if\u00a0was she from Surabaya\u00a0: menggunakan she karena menceritakan kembali<br><br>semoga membantu :)",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "1. kiki asked me what would i buy in the mall.<br>2. Mrs. Maria asked me can i speak English well<br>3. Yuda asked Tika was she from Surabaya<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "ubah-kalimat-tersebut-ke-dalam-bentuk-pasif-1-it-is-said-that-ma-237",
            "question": "Ubah kalimat tersebut ke dalam bentuk pasif    1. It is said that many people are homeless after floods\r\n2. People say that Arthur is very rich\r\n3. People say that he has 22 children\u00a0",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "1. It is said that many people are homeless after floods<br>-- ini udah pasif ya?\u00a0<br>Many people are homeless due to flood, it is said by the newspaper<br><br>2. People say that Arthur is very rich<br>Arthur is very rich, is said by people<br><span><br>3. People say that he has 22 children\u00a0<br>he has 22 children, is said by people\u00a0<br><br></span>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "sebutkan-kata-sifat-dari-pengelompokan-tersebut-sebanyak-banyak-851",
            "question": "Sebutkan kata sifat dari pengelompokan tersebut! (sebanyak-banyaknya)    menurut:1.Skin (Cool, Ho, ...)\r\n\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 2. Place (in,at,on,\u00a0...)\r\n\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 3. Age (New,old,\u00a0...)\r\n\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 4. Nose (sweet, smelling, ...)\r\n\r\nTolong kerjasamanya Friend's.. thanks so'much!",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Skin = cool, hot, soft, dirty, clean, rude, ugly, beautiful\nPlace : in, on, at, beside, behind, in front, between.\nAge : old, young, new,",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "their-motivationimprove-if-they-858",
            "question": "Their motivation...............(improve) if they..........................(kick) a goal during the first half",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "their motivation increases when the kick goal during the first half<br><br>kalau salah gak apa-apa ya<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "contoh-soal-soal-persuading-195",
            "question": "Contoh soal soal persuading",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Why don\u2019t you\ntry our special drink bandrek to warm up your body?\n\n\n\n\n<br><span>\nIf I were you, I\nwould \u2026 ?</span>\n<span>\n\u00a0I\u2019m sure you are\non the right track.?</span>\n\n\n<br><span>\n\u00a0<span>I bet you could\ndo it.?</span></span><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "pengertian-dan-contoh-adverb-of-frequency-256",
            "question": "Pengertian dan contoh adverb of frequency",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "adverb yang menggambarkan frekuensi seseorang melakukan suatu pekerjaan, misalnya setiap hari, atau beberapa kali dalam 1 bulan<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "pengertian\u00a0: kata keterangan yang menyatakan seberapa sering suatu kegiatan yang dilakukan.",
                    "attachments": [
                        "answer-attachments/pengertian-dan-contoh-adverb-of-frequency-256-1.gif"
                    ]
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "arrange-the-jumbled-words-to-form-meaningful-sentencesstarting-w-193",
            "question": "arrange the jumbled words to form meaningful sentences,starting with the underlined words. 1. phone-puppet-his-invite-the-I-number-my-see-Finto-know-will-if-show-to-I-at-place 2. and-holiday-Bali-if-have-will-his-Lombok-long-go-year-Mr. Kukuh-family-to-they-and-this-a \u00a0 mohon di bantu",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "2. Mr. Kukuh and his family will go to Bali and Lombok if they have a long holiday this year<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "apa-bahasa-inggrisnya-mengacak-acak-rambutnya-667",
            "question": "Apa Bahasa Inggrisnya mengacak-acak rambutnya?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "bahasa inggris nya adalah mess her/his hair",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "Ruffled/Mess his/her hair<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "tolong-describe-dengan-tema-my-beloved-home-523",
            "question": "Tolong describe dengan tema \"my beloved home\"",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "I live in an ordinary house, but I always feel that I belong here for no reason. My house really cozy, it has 4 rooms with AC inside, 1 kitchen, 3 bathrooms, 1 livingrooms, and a green garden in front of it. My mom always take care of this house. I think it&#039;s right that our house is our palace because we can do what we want no matter what. Two years ago, I almost moved to the other house because there was an accident, and sssttt I can&#039;t tell you, because it&#039;s secret. So I think that&#039;s all",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "apa-beda-auxilary-amp-operator-siapa-penemu-font-old-english-907",
            "question": "-Apa beda Auxilary &amp; Operator?    -Siapa penemu font Old English?\r\n -Kapan Bahasa Inggris masuk ke Indonesia?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "gaktau ee kak bntar takcarikan yha<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}